Derek C. Welty

weltyderek@gmail.com | □ 206-209-9934 | ♥ Seattle, WA | ♥ derekwelty.com | in linkedin.com/in/derekwelty

Summary _____

Senior Hardware Engineer with 10 years of experience in consumer electronics industries working in all phases of the development life cycle. Possesses a Master's degree in Electrical Engineering and a broad set of skills and experiences ranging from prototyping to PCB design to system validation. Highly self-motivated and solution-oriented technical contributor with a growth mindset and passion for problem solving.

Experience _

Microsoft Corporation

Redmond, WA

Sept 2019 - Present

SENIOR DESIGN VERIFICATION ENGINEER

- Owns targeted verification of XBOX systems and subsystems including SoC power management firmware
- Designed, integrated, and maintained automated test systems (Python, PowerShell, C++)
- Hardware prototype bring-up, debugging, and failure analysis
- · Use of statistical techniques to analyze large data sets and design experiments

Garmin International Olathe, KS

SENIOR DESIGN ENGINEER

- Mar 2017 Sept 2019
- · Conceptualized and materialized automotive mass production consumer infotainment electronics
- · Designed and developed complex PCBs with analog, digital, high-speed, audio, display, camera, wireless, capacitive touch and RF circuitry
- Project Engineer leading system design and coordinating interdisciplinary collaboration
- · Directed and collaborated with factory team in Taiwan to design for testing and manufacturability
- Tested and debugged hardware/software issues for technical root cause and corrective actions

DOE National Security Campus, Managed by Honeywell

Kansas City, MO Jan 2013 – Mar 2017

- Lead test engineer architecting/implementing hardware/software solutions for scalable test infrastructure
- Defined test plans and electrical verification methodologies for board level and top level systems
- Interfaced with government customers and supported earned value management project planning
- US Government Security Clearance

Sprint Nextel Corporation

Overland Park, KS May 2012 - Aug 2012

NETWORK ENGINEER INTERN

- Designed and implemented a VoIP Android IMS client using Java
- Debugged client/server communications by analyzing network packets and protocols
- Utilized network and streaming protocols such as UDP, SIP, and RTP

Cargill Corn Milling Inc Eddyville, IA

PRODUCTION MANAGEMENT ENGINEER CO-OP

May 2011 - Dec 2011

Oct 2010 - Mar 2015

- Served as a project engineer/manager for various factory installations • Focused on power, automation, and maintenance projects
- Hired and led a team of contractors to carry out construction projects

Lumate, LLC St. Louis, MO

- Created in-house and customer specific graphics for mobile applications (Android, iOS)
- Supported back-end web development (Python, jQuery, HTML)
- Interfaced directly with customers creating logos, flyers, posters, apparel designs, and brochures

Education _

Missouri University of Science & Technology

Rolla, MO

MS IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Aug 2013 - May 2018

Digital Network Design, Wireless Networks, Resilient Networks, Network Performance Analysis and Modeling, Stochastic Signal Analysis, Power Electronics, Advanced Electromagnetics, Microwave Engineering, Analog CMOS Design GPA: 4.00/4.00

Missouri University of Science & Technology

Rolla, MO

Aug 2008 - Dec 2012

BS IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING, MINOR IN MATHEMATICS

GPA: 3.93/4.00

Skills_

Technologies: Ethernet, USB, WiFi, BT, I2C, SPI, MIPI, GPS, UART, PCIe

Programming: VB.NET, Python, Java, MATLAB, Arduino, Github, Subversion, TestStand, ADB, VISA, PowerShell Lab Equipment: Oscilloscopes, multimeters, network analyzers, logic analyzers, power supplies, Raspberry Pi, Arduino, PXI

Software Tools: Schematic capture, PCB layout, Mentor Graphics, CADSTAR, OrCad, SPICE, Solidworks

Special Training: Advanced GNSS/GPS, Radar Systems Certificate, MIL-STD 1553
Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, LaTeX, HTML, Bootstrap
Miscellaneous: MS Office, Android, Linux, Windows, Atlassian suite, Azure Dev Ops

Awards _____

2016 **Outstanding Engineer Award**, Honeywell Aerospace

Patents_

2019 **US10447297B1**, Electronic Device and Method for Compressing Sampled Data